My name is Brain of Terror and I am
an NSO at Dublin Roller Derby.
I am also one of the scoreboard
developers.
In this set of videos we are going to be
looking at version 4 of the Scoreboard.
This is the latest release for
the whole pile of new features
so in these videos I am not going
to try and cover everything at once.
Roller derby is a relatively
complex game in terms of stats,
there is lots of business rules
and so on to go into
so you might see something at screen
I don’t discuss or that’s a little off
that’s just because it’s going to be
in a later video.
So the big thing about version 4 of the
scoreboard is all the stats support.
There’s now full WFTDA
statsbook support
which is largely due to Speedy
Convalesce who is with Star Track.
Erm, so, we will be looking at all of that,
like Penalty Tracking,
Line-up Tracking and so on.
If you have any questions
about the scoreboard
the best place to ask is on the Derby
Scoreboard Facebook group
which I’ll put a link to in the
description below.
In terms of history
CRG stands for Carolina Roller Girls
who started the scoreboard some
10-ish years ago.
They are no longer involved but
we still have the name,
and we are on like third or fourth set
of developers,
which is pretty good going as open
source projects go.
So I hope you find these videos useful.