My name is Brain of Terror and I
am an NSO at Dublin Roller Derby.
In this video, I'm going to look at
downloading and running the Scoreboard.
You can go to your favourite search
engine, type in "roller derby scoreboard"
and there should be a link to GitHub.
It should take you to this address,
I will include a link in the description.
The important thing here is the
Releases link,
which is going to show you all
the official releases.
These videos are about version 4 of
the Scoreboard
which isn't actually out when I am
making these videos
because I need to make the videos
before we put it out
But principles are the same. So if I
scroll down here
there is a section called Assets.
Now, we don't want the source code,
what you want here is
crg-scoreboard_VERSION.zip
so you can click that to download.
Here's version 4 that I have
downloaded earlier.
Now, you could click into this to look at it,
however that would be incorrect
because this is a ZIP file
and what you want to do is extract it
I am using something called XFCE as
my window manager,
whatever you are using, whether it's
Windows, or Mac or some form of Linux
there should be some way to
extract a ZIP file.
In any case, you should now have a folder,
and you can open it up.
I'm on Linux, so I can run scoreboard.sh
If I was on OSX, on the Mac, I would also
run scoreboard.sh
and for Windows it's just
scoreboard-Windows.exe
So basically, Windows users use
scoreboard-Windows.exe,
everyone else uses scoreboard.sh
Click that up, and it should run !
Now, it has a whole pile of ways
to access it
almost always you're going to
want localhost:8000
and there's the scoreboard.
Most systems these days will
already have Java installed
because CRG is a Java application
you may need however to download JDK
or JRE in order to get things running.