My name is Brain of Terror and I am
an NSO at Dublin Roller Derby.
In this video, I'm going to
show you the absolute bare minimum
you need to know to run the Scoreboard
in less than 5 minutes.
So, let's see what the bare minimum is.
Here's the rules
They say we need the period clock,
the Jam clock and the official score.
Everything else is nice to have. Great !
So let's open up the Operator panel
This dialog will come up,
press X
At some point, the Jam Timer will do
their rolling whistle,
five seconds,
and start the jam.
Lead is declared. Lead is not one of the
three things we care about, so nothing to do.
Some points are put up.
This will fade...
More points are put up.
Now, skaters can only go around the track
so fast, so that's fine
And then maybe the jam is called,
so the fourth whistle
is when we want to
press the button.
twit twit twit TWIT,  twit twit twit twit,
twit twit twit twit
So fourth whistle, not the first
whistle, not the twelfth whistle.
So, here we go.
The official Jam clock and so on is here.
This is the lineup clock, the Jam
Timer should be looking at this,
and on 25 seconds, they should be going "5 seconds",
...
5 seconds
Twit !
So, you press "Start Jam" when they "twit"
which should be at 30 seconds.
But you press it when they actually "twit".
So here we are in the next jam,
maybe there's some points here
then we stop the jam, and hop,
there was a point there at the end.
Grand.
What if I need to adjust the points ?
Usually, you can use these buttons,
but you can only go down so far.
So, if you need to go a bit further back in time
to adjust the score, you can do it down here.
You can click anywhere you see a number
that is bigger than zero and change it.
Just one thing to watch,
you'll notice it says 4+0,
that first 4 is actually over here
in the No Initial column.
So if I wanted to change that,
I need to click here,
rather than here which is just a 2.
This is a paperwork thing,
don't worry about it too much.
So, let's say we are going
into the next Jam,
here we go, scores are over here, nice and correct, and we stop the jam.
Now let's say there is going to be a Timeout.
We'll press the Timeout button.
We don't care what sort of Timeout it is,
that's not one of the three things we care about.
We do however care about the Period Clock.
It's possible we are a bit off,
In which case the Jam Timer may ask us
to put a bit of time back on the clock
which we can do with these buttons here.
Fine !
Now.
At some point, the Timeout will end, we'll
have a rolling whistle, and we end the Timeout.
There will be a 5 seconds call,
and the Jam will start.
Grand.
Now, this is only a 5-minute video so
we are not going to do an entire period
You might stop the Jam, and I'm just
going to advance time
Start Jam...
... you'll add a few more points...
We are coming to the end of period 1.
There was less than 30 seconds left
on the period clock, so everything goes red to tell you
that there shouldn't normally be another
jam in the period unless someone
calls a Timeout or there's a
discretionary Jam or something.
That's fine. So, otherwise that
would just be a zero, cool,
to advance and we are now
in intermission.
An important thing to note : if you
start a Jam now, it will go in Period 1
because there might be a discretionary Jam, or a Timeout or something.
If you want to go into period 2, there needs to be
less than a minute on the intermission clock.
So, I'm just gonna set this down to a second,
intermission is fired, going into period 2,
I start the Jam.
There's some points.
I stop the Jam, and so on and so forth, exact same as before.
I'm once again going
to advance the Period Clock.
And now we're at the end of the game,
we'll presume there's no more Jams.
You'll notice this "End of Period
Controls" is flashing.
So you click on that, and what you do is,
you wait for the Score Keepers and
and the Jam Refs to confirm
that the scores are final,
and if there's an Overtime Jam,
Start Jam is right over there
Once it's all confirmed and all, you
click "Unofficial Score"
and this will now say Final Score.
So, that is the bare minimum you need
to know in How to Operate the Scoreboard
in less than 5 minutes.